nest.com 2013-11-28

# Privacy Statement | Nest

## At Nest, we take your privacy seriously.

This document explains what kind of information Nest Labs, Inc. and its subsidiaries and affiliates (collectively, “Nest”) collects and stores, including Personally Identifiable Information (i.e., data that can be reasonably linked to a specific individual or household) in connection with the operation of the Nest Learning Thermostat™ and Nest Protect™ Smoke + Carbon Monoxide Alarm (collectively, “Nest Products”). 

We pledge to:

  1. _Be transparent_  about the different types of information we collect and how we use them.
  2. _Ask your permission_  before sharing your Personally Identifiable Information with third parties for purposes other than to provide Nest’s services, and to do so only when we think they will provide you with a welcome additional service.
  3. _Use best-in-class data security tools_  to keep your data safe and protect the Nest Products from unauthorized access.

By using this service, you agree to allow us to collect and process information as described below.

**What information does the Nest Learning Thermostat collect?**

The Nest Learning Thermostat collects:

  * Information input during setup
  * Environmental data from the Nest Learning Thermostat’s sensors
  * Direct temperature adjustments to the device
  * Heating and cooling usage information
  * Technical information from the device

__Information input during setup__ : When you install the Nest Learning Thermostat, you’ll be asked several questions about your home to help create an initial program of temperature settings. For example, we’ll ask questions like, “Is Nest located in a home or business?”. We’ll also ask for your postal or zip code so that Nest can retrieve weather information for your neighborhood. In addition, the Nest Learning Thermostat pulls information directly from your heating and cooling (HVAC) system to learn its capabilities – such as if it has heating and cooling or is a heating-only system. Answering these questions helps us to set up an initial program that will keep you comfortable.

__Environmental data from the Nest Learning Thermostat’s sensors__ : We collect data from several sensors built into the Nest Learning Thermostat. These sensors collect data such as current temperature, humidity and ambient light in the room. They can also sense whether something in the room is moving. By recording this information, the Nest Learning Thermostat can make you comfortable when you are at home and save energy when you are away. For example, if the Nest Learning Thermostat senses a light being switched on or that you’ve entered the room after an extended period of time, it can adjust the setting to a preferred temperature, based on an assumption that you’ve just woken up or returned home. Similarly, if the light goes off or no one is moving in the room, the Nest Learning Thermostat may turn the temperature down sometimes to save you energy.

__Direct temperature adjustments to the device__ : If you change the temperature on Nest, it records and feeds that information to the Nest Learning Thermostat algorithms to learn your desired comfort level under different situations.

__Heating and cooling usage information__ : Every time your system turns on and off, the Nest Learning Thermostat records the time and duration during which it was on in order to offer you features such as usage history.

__Technical information from the device__ : In order to improve your experience over time and help troubleshoot any problem you may encounter with the Nest Learning Thermostat, we record your Nest Learning Thermostat model and serial number, software version, and technical information such as battery charge level.

**What information does the Nest Protect collect?**

The Nest Protect collects:

  * Information input during setup
  * Environmental data from the Nest Protect’s sensors
  * Technical information from the device

__Information input during setup__ : When you install the Nest Protect, you’ll be asked where in your home you’re installing Nest Protect. This will enable the Nest Protect to inform you of where danger is occurring.

__Environmental data from the Nest Protect’s sensors__ : We collect data from several sensors built into the Nest Protect. These sensors collect data such as smoke and CO levels, current temperature, humidity and ambient light in the room. They can also sense whether something in the room is moving. By recording this information, the Nest Protect can detect smoke and CO in your home, give you alarms and warnings, and provide the ability to silence a nuisance alarm by waving your hand. For example, If Nest Protect sees that smoke or CO levels are rising, it will give you a Heads Up before the danger reaches emergency alarm levels and tell you what the danger is.

__Technical information from the device__ : In order to improve your experience over time and help troubleshoot any problem you may encounter with the Nest Protect, we record your Nest Protect model and serial number, software version, and technical information such as sensor status and battery charge level.

**What information is shared among multiple connected Nest Products?**

If you have multiple Nest products interfacing with one another, the products will share certain information among one another, such as data on whether something in the room is moving, temperature data, and the occurrence of smoke or CO alarms. By sharing data on whether something in the room is moving, the products better assess if you are away from home so temperature can be reduced you can save more energy.

**If a Nest Product interfaces to third party products and services, will information be shared?**

Over time, Nest may provide the opportunity for you to interface Nest Products to one or more third party products and services, which will involve the exchange of information from your Nest Product. Your explicit consent and authorization will be required for this interface, and will be revocable by you at any time.

**What additional information does Nest collect and store when a user connects a Nest Product to the Internet?**

To access your Nest Product over the Internet from a computer, a smartphone or a tablet, you will need to connect it to your Wi-Fi network. During setup, the Nest Product will ask for your Wi-Fi network name (SSID) and password to connect to the Internet. It will save this information on the device, along with your IP address, so that you can access it and control it from your computer, smartphone or tablet, and so that it can communicate with Nest servers and download software updates.

Once connected to your Wi-Fi network, your Nest Product regularly uploads to Nest cloud servers the data mentioned above (excluding your Wi-Fi password) to provide you with the service.

Additionally, when you create a Nest Account, we collect and store your email address. From that point forward, your email address is used for communications from Nest.

Like most Internet sites, we routinely record log entries (including information such as your IP address) and technical information (such as your browser type and version) when your browser, mobile device or Nest Product contacts our servers. These log files are used for troubleshooting and are stored on our cloud servers.

**How does Nest use the information it collects?**

We use this information to provide and improve Nest Products and services, including information and recommendations about your energy use. We may use your email address to send you this information, or to ask you to participate in surveys about your Nest use. We use service providers to perform some of these functions. Those service providers are restricted from sharing your information for any other purpose.

We use industry-standard methods to keep this information safe and secure while transmitted over your home network and through the Internet to our cloud servers.

**With whom does Nest share my information?**

Under no circumstance do we share Personally Identifiable Information for any commercial or marketing purpose unrelated to the delivery of Nest Products and services without asking you first. Period. We do not rent or sell our customer lists.

Our service technicians and other Nest employees have supervised access to your information so they can answer your questions if you contact us for help and so they can monitor our servers for technical problems.

Except as described herein, we will only provide Personally Identifiable Information about our users to a third party if required to do so by law, or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with state and federal laws or respond to a court order, subpoena, or search warrant.

We may share your aggregated and anonymous information in a variety of ways, including to publish trends about energy use and conservation, to help utilities provide demand-response services and to generally improve our system. We’ve taken steps to ensure that the information cannot be linked back to you and we require our partners to keep all information in its anonymous form.

Your personal information may be collected, processed and stored by Nest or its service providers in the United States and other countries where our servers reside. As a result, your personal information may be subject to legal requirements, including lawful requirements to disclose personal information to government authorities, in those jurisdictions. If you select an outside party for the purchase, installation, or service of your Nest device and share your personal information, we cannot control the collection, storage or sharing of information collected by that party. For example, if you bought your thermostat from a retailer, they may collect personal information as part of the transaction. Or the party that installed the device may retain information that you provided to them to assist them in servicing the device if needed. Always check the privacy policies for any company that collects your personal information.

**How long does Nest save my personal information and how can I delete it?**

Nest stores your Personally Identifiable Information on Nest’s cloud servers for as long as you remain a Nest customer in order to provide you with the service. As described above, some information is stored directly on the Nest device. All information is encrypted and cannot easily be accessed. You can delete the information on the Nest device by resetting it to the defaults (using Reset in the Settings menu).

If you want to delete your Personally Identifiable Information from Nest’s servers, please contact us at [privacy@nest.com](mailto:privacy@nest.com). Because of the way we maintain certain services, after your information is deleted, backup copies may linger for some time before they are deleted.

If you have any questions, please contact us at [privacy@nest.com](mailto:privacy@nest.com).

* * *

Policy active as of October 8, 2013. Review previous policies here.

* * *
